# Rohan French

--◊--

## **Institutional Address**

Faculty of Philosophy University of Groningen Oude Boteringestraat 52 9712 GL Groningen - The Netherlands E-MAIL: rohan.french@gmail.com

URL: https://sites.google.com/site/rohanfrench/

SKYPE: rohan.french

DATE OF BIRTH: January 31, 1984

NATIONALITY: Australian

#### AREAS OF SPECIALIZATION

Philosophical Logic • Philosophy of Logic • Metaphysics

### Areas of Competence

Formal Logic • Philosophy of Language.

## **CURRENT POSITION**

Postdoctoral Researcher working with Catarina Dutilh Novaes on the "Roots of Deduction" project in the Department of Theoretical Philosophy in the Faculty of Philosophy at the University of Groningen on formal aspects of the built-in opponent conception of deduction.

### PREVIOUS POSITIONS

2013-2014 Research Assista

2014

2011-2012

Research Assistant working with Greg Restall & Jen Davoren at The University of Melbourne on adapting the undergraduate logic course UNIBIOOO2 Logic: Language and Information into a pair of massively open online courses delivered via Coursera (resulting in https://class.coursera.org/logic1-001/ and https://class.coursera.org/logic2-001/).

Visiting Research Scholar, at Center for the Advancement of Logic, its Philosophy, History & Applications and Department of Logic and Philosophy of Science, University of California Irvine.

(Winter Quarter)

Research Associate, Department of Philosophy & Bioethics, Monash University.

## Education

## 2007-2011 PhD in Philosophy

Department of Philosophy and Bioethics, Monash University.

- Title: "Translational Embeddings in Modal Logic" (url: http://arrow.monash.edu.au/hdl/1959.1/474593)
- Degree Awarded: 17th January 2011
- Advisors: Graham Oppy, Lloyd Humberstone
- Examiners: Alasdair Urquhart (Toronto), Stephen Kuhn (Georgetown).

#### ABSTRACT

Often when we do philosophy we want to define less well understood notions with which we are concerned in terms of those which we have a much firmer grasp on. Hence, to take a classical example, we often try to define knowledge in terms of belief (and some auxiliary notions such as truth, justification and so on). Such definitions give rise to translations, functions which map the terms to be explained to their intended (simpler) explanation, and it is these which were our objects of study.

In particular we focused on providing a systematic study of the formal uses of translations between logics, and what they can tell us about the logics involved. Our focus was on propositional modal logics, both for reasons of explanatory simplicity, and also as modal logic remains one of the best formal tools we have for explicating a wide variety of live philosophical problems

2002-2006 Bachelor of Arts (Hons)/Bachelor of Computer Science, Monash University

## Grants, Honors & Awards

2010	Dean's Award for Best Sessional Teacher in the School of Philosophical, Historical and Interna-
	tional Studies

2010	Monash Research Graduate School Postgraduate Publication Award
2007-2010	Australian Research Council (ARC) Postgraduate Research Scholarship
2007	Camo Jackson Award for Best Honours in Philosophy, Monash University

2005 Scholarship to attend Australian National University (ANU) Logic Summer School

## Publications & Talks

## JOURNAL ARTICLES

2014

201X	French, R., "Sequent Calculi for Urn Logic", accepted for publication in The Journal of Logic, Language
	and Information.

French, R. and Humberstone, L., "An Observation Concerning Porte's Rule in Modal Logic", accepted for publication in *The Bulletin of the Section of Logic*.

French, R. and Ripley, D., "Contractions of Noncontractive Consequence Relations", forthcoming in Review of Symbolic Logic. [DOI]

French, R., "In the Mood for **S4**: The Expressive Power of the Subjunctive Modal Language in Weak Background Logics", forthcoming in *Studia Logica* [DOI]

French, R., "Review of A.A. Rini and M. J. Cresswell 'The World-Time Parallel'", Australasian Journal of Philosophy, Vol. 92, 802-805. [DOI]

French, R., "Expressive Power, Mood, and Actuality", Synthese, Vol. 190, 1689-1699. [Doi]

French, R. (2012), "Denumerably Many Post-Complete Normal Modal Logics with Additional Propositional Constants", Notre Dame Journal of Formal Logic, Vol. 53, 549-556.

French, R. (2012), "An Argument Against General Validity?", Thought, Vol. 1, 4–9.

French, R. and Humberstone, L. (2009), "Partial Confirmation of a Conjecture on the Boxdot Translation in Modal logic", *Australasian Journal of Logic*, Vol. 7, 56–61.

French, R. (2009), "A Simplified Embedding of **E** into Monomodal **K**", *Logic Journal of the IGPL*, Vol. 17, 421–428, 2009.

French, R. (2008), "The Logic of Eventual Permanence for Unending Linear Time", *The Notre Dame Journal of Formal Logic*, Vol. 49, No 2, 137–142

#### PUBLICATIONS UNDER REVIEW

French, R., "An Argument for the Ontological Innocence of Mereology" French, R. and Humberstone, L., "Note on Forster on Definite Descriptions"

## PUBLICATIONS IN PREPARATION

French, R., "Predicate Logic with Explicit Scope Markers"

French, R., "Proof Theory for Contingent Existence"

French, R., "Models for Anti-Positionalism"

French, R., "Truth without Assumption"

#### **TALKS**

Sept 2014	Melbourne, W. Lloyd Humberstone "Inomas Forster on Definite Descriptions", Melbourne Logic
	Group Logic Day.
May 2014	Melbourne, "Modal Logics with Statability Operators: Variations on a Priorian Theme", Melbourne
	Logic Group Logic Day.

U.C. Irvine, "Predicate Logic with Explicit Scope Markers", UC Irvine Logic and Philosophy of Science Colloquium.

Nov 2013 Melbourne, "Predicate Logic with Explicit Scope Markers", Melbourne Logic Group Logic Day.
Nov 2012 Monash, "The Ontological Innocence of Mereology", Monash Workshop on the Metaphysics of Time.

Sept 2012 Melbourne, "Sequent Calculi for Urn Logic", Melbourne Logic Group.

June 2012 Sydney, "Kaplan's Monsters–The Case of Fixedly", Australasian Association of Logic Conference.

June 2012 Melbourne, "Proof Theory for Contingent Existence", Melbourne Logic Group.

Apr 2012 U.C. Irvine, "In the Mood for **S4**", Invited presentation at Workshop on Actuality and Subjunctivity organised by K.F. Wehmeier.

Nov 2011 Kioloa, "The Logical Argument Against Quantifier Variance", Australian Metaphysics Conference.
Oct 2011 Monash, "The Logical Argument Against Quantifier Variance", Monash University Staff Seminar
Oct 2011 Melbourne, "Denumerably Many Post-Complete Normal Modal Logics with Additional Propositional Constants", Melbourne Logic Group.

Dec 2010 Melbourne, "Expressive Power, Mood and Actuality", Melbourne Logic Group.

Oct 2007 Melbourne, "The Range of Translations and the Problem of Maximality", Melbourne Logic Group.

## Teaching

## As Lecturer

S1 2014	Lecturer for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and Paradox (University of Melbourne)
S2 2011	Guest Lecturer (Basic Modal Logic and Normal Modal Logics) for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and
	Paradox (University of Melbourne)
S2 2011	Guest Lecturer for PHIL40013 Uncertainty, Vagueness and Disagreement Honours seminar on Fatalism
	(University of Melbourne)
S2 2010	Guest Lecturer (Nozick on Skepticism) for PHL1080 Time. Self and Mind.

si 2010 Lecturer and Course Coordinator for PHL3590 Mind and Meaning (Monash University).

As Tutor

S1 2014

	Head Tutor for UNIB10002 Logic: Language and Information (Melbourne University).
S2 2013	Tutor for PHIL20030 Meaning, Possibility and Paradox (University of Melbourne).
S2 2013	Tutor for ATS1838 Philosophy: Introduction C (Logic) (Monash University).
S1 2013	Tutor for ATS2866 Symbolic Logic (Monash University).
S1 2013	Head Tutor for UNIB10002 Logic: Language and Information (Melbourne University).
S1 2012	Head Tutor for UNIB10002 Logic: Language and Information (Melbourne University).
S1 2011	Tutor for ATS1833 Thinking (Monash University).
S2 2010	Tutor for PHL1080 Time, Self and Mind (Monash University).
S1 2008	Tutor for PHL1030 Thinking: Analysing Arguments (Monash University)

# Service to the profession

Referee for Australasian Journal of Logic, Australasian Journal of Philosophy, Erkenntnis, Journal of Applied Non-Classical Logic, and Logique et Analyse.

## Referees

LLOYD HUMBERSTONE Reader Monash University Clayton, Victoria, Australia e-mail: Lloyd.Humberstone@monash.edu

Professor Greg Restall Professor University of Melbourne Parkville, Victoria, Australia e-mail: restall@unimelb.edu.au

PROFESSOR KAI WEHMEIER
Professor
University of California, Irvine
Irvine, California, United States of America
e-mail: wehmeier@uci.edu